卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle
请注意  在跟随贝克特探长研究你下本小说的过程中  如果你受伤了
Be advised, if you get injured following Detective Beckett to research your next novel,
你无权起诉政府
You cannot sue the city.
如果你中枪了 也无权起诉政府
If you get shot, you cannot sue the city.
如果你因此丧命
If you get killed--
我那毫无生气的遗体更无权起诉政府
My lifeless remains cannot sue the city.
是你的继承人  卡塞尔先生
Your heirs, Mr. Castle.
我是现在就杀了他  还是等他签完协议呢
Do I have to wait for him to sign, or can I shoot him now?
卡塞尔先生  签弃权证书需要谨慎考虑
Mr. Castle, these waivers are serious business.
或许向你的律师咨询一下
Perhaps you'd feel more comfortable
会对你比较好
By referring the matter to your attorney?
别开玩笑了  他怎么可能让我签这些
What, are you kidding? He'd never let me sign these.
不过  幸好他的工作只是帮我解决麻烦
But fortunately, it's his job to get me out of trouble
我自找麻烦就与他无关
And not to prevent me from getting into it.
好  在哪儿
Yeah. Where?
好的  我马上到
All right, I'm on my way.
等等  你要去哪儿
Whoa, wait. Uh, where are you going?
-有工作要忙  -什么  我们有案子了吗
- I have work to do. - What? We have a case?
是我的案子  你要搞定这些文件
No, I have a case. You have paperwork.
-什么情况  -罗森伯格太太  住在9楼E
- So?  - Mrs. Rosenberg, 9-E here,
她下来想用干衣机
Comes down to put her clothes in the dryer,
但发现里面有衣服
Finds it's occupied.
一个半小时后再来  不想再等了
Comes down a half an hour later and she's had enough,
决定自己动手解决
Decides to take matters into her own hands.
拜托  你是说
Come on. You're telling me that
一位老太太为了台干衣机杀人吗
An old lady killed someone over a busy dryer?
什么  不是  她只是等急了
What? No, she's just tired of waitin' around.
所以她打开了干衣机
So she opens up the dryer
想把别人的衣服拿出来
To take the other person's clothes out,
却发现了这位小姐蜷在里面  浑身绒毛
Find Miss fluff and fold here instead.
不要探究别人洗的衣服
Now if that's not a cautionary tale
如果这还不算是个警世恒言
About poking around someone else's laundry,
那我也搞不懂了
I don't know what is.
伙计  这可是礼貌问题
Dude, there is an etiquette involved.
如果衣服干了
If the clothes were dry,
罗森伯格太太完全有权把它们放进篮子
Mrs. Rosenberg had every right to put 'em in the basket.
如果你想说这衣服是她折的
Now if you're gonna tell me that she folded 'em,
那这事有点恐怖了
Then it gets a little creepy.
抱歉  如果有人不经我同意
I'm sorry, someone starts rootin' around my underwear
就乱翻我的内衣
Without an invitation,
那是非常非常不卫生的
I'm taking that as a serious breach of hygiene.
我以为你参加突击队了   埃斯波西托
I thought you went commando, Esposito.
季节工作
Well... Seasonal thing.
尊重死者  把她抬出来吧
All right, let's get her out of there with some dignity.
让案发现场部门过来
And we need C.S.U. to come down here,
漂白液的瓶子要带回实验室
And the bleach bottle will have to go down to the lab,
有可能有指纹和照片
And probably prints and photographs,
虽然不知道
Although I don't know
在公共场所  这些能有多大用
If it's gonna do us much good in a public area.
我猜她住这儿
I'm guessing she lived here?
她在12楼F当保姆
Worked. 12-F. She's the nanny.
以为把我扔在警局了  是吗
Thought you ditched me back at the precinct, didn't you?
别这样  干衣机里发现死去的保姆
Come on. Nanny Mcdead is found on spin dry.
你不觉得上尉会让我参与这事吗
You don't think the captain's gonna let me in on that story?
你说的对  卡塞尔
You're right, Castle.
我错了
My bad.
像这样在你的阴影笼罩下办案的日子
Exactly how much longer do I have to expect you
我到底还得熬多久
To be shadowing me on my cases like this?
很难说  可能是我写新角色的时候
Hard to say. When I'm writing a new character,
但说不准灵感几时来敲门
There's no telling when inspiration might strike.
我以为我是你的灵感
I thought I was your inspiration.
你当然是了  探长  从很多方面都是
Oh, you are, detective, and in so many ways.
很快就会有灵感敲打你
Yeah, well, your inspiration might strike you
快得超乎想象
Sooner than you think.
保姆的名字是莎拉·曼宁
Nanny's name was Sara Manning.
她为彼得森一家工作了两年
She worked for the Petersons about two years.
门卫是我小说的狂热粉丝
The doorman is a huge fan of my work.
彼得森太太
Mrs. Peterson?
凯特·贝克特探长  纽约警察
Detective Kate Beckett, NYPD.
我能问些
I was wondering if I could ask you
有关莎拉·曼宁的问题吗
Some questions about Sara Manning.
当然  请进
Of course. Please come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
理查德·卡塞尔  只是纽约公民
Richard Castle. Just N.Y.
亲爱的  爸爸妈妈要和别人谈点事
Sweetie, mommy and daddy need to talk to some people,
不过我们就在这儿
But we'll be right out here.
我们还没告诉他发生了什么
We still haven't told him what happened.
不知道怎么开口
We just don't know how.
莎拉和他关系很好
Sara was very close with him.
她天生就能和孩子们相处很好
She just had-- has a- a gift with kids, you know?
可爱的女孩
She was such a lovely girl.
-我很抱歉  -学校打电话到我的办公室
- I'm very sorry.  - The school called me at my office
说莎拉没有去接贾斯廷
When Sara didn't come to pick up Justin.
于是我打了她的手机
I-I tried her cell phone,
但只转到语音信箱
But it went straight to voice mail.
然后我打了家里  但是是答录机
Then I tried here, but the machine picked up.
所以我叫了出租车  去了学校
So I hopped in a cab and went to the school.
到家的时候  警察就已经到了
When we got home, the police were already here.
最后一次看见莎拉是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Sara?
我丈夫昨晚回家时见到过她
My husband saw her last night when he got home.
我们每天早上自己送贾斯廷去学校
We take Justin to school every morning,
所以她到这儿的时候  我们一般都不在家
So we're usually gone by the time she gets here.
大概是几点
And what time is that?
今天本该是11点的
Today it would have been 11:00.
莎拉来整理下  送洗贾斯廷的衣服
Sara straightens up, does Justin's laundry
然后2点左右去学校接他
And then picks him up from school about 2:00.
我们俩有一个回家吃晚饭
One of us is then home for dinner.
昨天轮到我丈夫回家
Last night it was my husband's turn.
那么你是最后一个见到莎拉的人了
So then you were the last one to see Sara?
我想应该是的
I- I guess so.
她有提到最近有什么麻烦吗
Did she mention any problems she was having,
-比如是男朋友  -莎拉的男朋友吗
- Uh, maybe a boyfriend?  - Sara's boyfriend?
门卫说
The-- the doorman said
警察认为是非法闯入
The- the police told them that it was a break- in,
那一般是由陌生人所为
Which usually means a stranger did it.
我们还不确定发生了什么
We can't be sure what happened.
可能不确定  但数据显示
Well, maybe not, but statistically speaking,
凶手很可能是她认识的人
Much greater likelihood that it was someone she knew.
天啊
Oh, my god.
再次申明  我们还不确定谁涉及此案
Again, we can't be certain who was involved.
-她是有个男朋友  -叫布兰特  但分手了
- But she had a boyfriend.  - Brent. But they broke up.
什么时候
And when was that?
一个月前  但莎拉从没说过
About a month ago, but Sara never said
这事儿有什么麻烦的
There was any trouble or anything like that.
他叫布兰特吗
Brent-- that was his name?
-是的  -知道他姓什么吗
- Yes.  - Do you know his last name?
我没听莎拉提起过
Uh, I don't think Sara ever mentioned it.
也没和我提过
Not to me, either.
谢谢两位的宝贵时间
Thank you both so much for your time.
乐意效劳
Of course.
-卡塞尔  走吧  -什么  就这样吗
- Castle, let's go.  - But-- that's it?
就这样
That's it.
你们知道有什么方法
Oh, do you know of any way
能联系莎拉的父母吗
I could reach Sara's parents?
天啊  我竟然都没想过
Oh, god. I hadn't even thought of that.
抱歉  我们没有他们的号码
I- I'm sorry. We don't have their number.
他们住在亚特兰大
Yeah. They live in Atlanta.
她圣诞节的时候会去陪他们
She was with them over Christmas.
莎拉有什么东西留下的吗
What about Sara's things?
这是她的包和外套
There's her bag and her jacket.
也许我能带回去  查查她的手机
Maybe I could take it and check her cell phone?
我为什么不能留下来  我还有好多问题
Why couldn't me stick around? I had a lot more questions.
因为我喜欢自己先去调查
Because I actually like to investigate things myself first.
而且  他们都不会逃走的
Besides, neither of them is going anywhere.
手机不在这里
Well, there's no cell phone in here.
或许在洗衣房或者干衣机里
Maybe it's in the laundry room or in the dryer.
如果在的话  案发现场部门会找到的
Well, if it is, C.S.U. will find it.
她的证件还是乔治亚州
She's still got her Georgia license.
真的要由你负责通知她父母吗
Are you really the one who has to call her parents?
生活比写小说要难多了吧  卡塞尔
Easier to write about than to live through, huh, Castle?
三个男人围着台电脑
Three men huddled around a computer.
最好不是看色情片  如果是的话  算上我
That better not be porn, and if it is, I want in.
埃斯波西托和瑞恩调出了后门的
Esposito and Ryan pulled security tape
电梯监控录象
From an elevator in the rear entrance.
前门的门卫24小时值班
Front door has a 24- Hour doorman.
这是电梯里的录象
This is the elevator's cam.
被害人拿着洗衣篮进了电梯
Our victim gets on the elevator with the laundry basket.
下去地下室
Takes it down to the basement,
把那孩子的衣服放进洗衣机
Puts the kid's clothes in the washer.
几分钟后  回到电梯
A few minutes later, gets back on,
直接上去  回到公寓
Goes all the way back up to the apartment.
40分钟后  又进了电梯
Then about 40 minutes later, rides the elevator back down
去了地下室
To the basement again.
大概是把衣服拿出来
Figure probably to take the kid's clothes
放到干衣机里
Out of the washer, put 'em in the dryer.
不过她再也没出现在镜头里
Camera never picks her up again.
之后一小时内  坐电梯去地下室的
Only other person to ride the elevator down all the way
唯一一个人  只有那位
To the basement during the next hour was the old lady
发现尸体的老太太
Who found the body.
就是说  凶手一定是走的楼梯间
So whoever attacked her must have used the stairwell,
否则监视录象里会有他的
Otherwise the camera would have caught him.
那天有三个维修工当班
We got three maintenance workers on duty that day.
今晚我们会查查他们
We'll run their names tonight.
为什么只查工人
Why only run the workers' names?
不查查所有的邻居
Why not run all the neighbors' names?
这么说有什么根据
What are you basing that on?
根据是
I'm basing that on...
凶手是邻居的话  故事会更精彩
The neighbor would make a better story.
拜托  在城市里
No, come on. What do any of us know
我们有谁认识自己的邻居
About our neighbors in this city?
你觉得山姆之子(纽约州连环杀手)的邻居
You think the guy living next door to the son of Sam
会知道他住在山姆之子的隔壁吗
Knew he was living next door to the son of Sam?
他说的对  伯科威茨(山姆之子的姓氏)住的楼
He's right. Neighbors in Berkowitz's building
没人知道他是连环杀手  山姆之子
Had no idea he was the son of Sam killer.
谢谢  那个住在8楼B的人呢
Thank you. What about the guy in 8-B?
谁
Who?
8楼B的  那个安静的家伙
8-B. Quiet guy.
你每天都能见到他  但是你从没注意过他
You see him every day, only you never notice him.
不过他注意到了莎拉
But he noticed Sara.
她年轻貌美
She's young, beautiful,
是他那样的男人
The kind of girl that a guy like him
永远得不到的
Would never have a chance with.
我们都认识这样的女孩  对不对
We all know girls like that, don't we?
一开始这只是个游戏  查出她的行程
Well, at first it's just a game. Figure out her schedule.
什么时间去洗衣房  什么时候形单影只
When does she do her laundry? When is she alone?
直到事情继续发展
Until it becomes something more,
发展到他无法控制的地步
Something that he can't control.
很明显  他走楼梯
Well, he uses the stairs, obviously,
就逃开了电梯里的摄像头
To avoid the elevator's cameras.
然后他就藏身在阴影里
And then he just waits,
等待着
Concealed in the shadows.
她踏入洗衣房的一瞬间
When she comes into that laundry room,
他猛地扑了上来
He pounces.
他看着她那双空洞  毫无生气的眼睛
When he looked into her vacant, lifeless eyes,
他想要告诉她  他从没想过要杀她
He wanted to tell her he never meant to kill her.
他所想要的只是一点点注意
All he ever wanted was to be noticed.
就在那时  他的皮肤感觉到了干衣机的热度
That's when he felt the heat of that dryer on his skin.
他抱起她那柔软无力的身体
So he picks up her limp body in his arms
轻轻地放了进去
And gently places it inside.
当他发现口袋里的那25美分时
He almost smiled at his good fortune
他为自己的好运而展露微笑
When he found the quarter in his pocket,
悄悄把硬币放进去
Slipping it into the slot.
为自己争取了时间  来做他最擅长的事
Buying him the time to do what he does best...
消失
Disappear.
说说而已  更好的故事  要咖啡吗
Just saying, better story. Coffee?
去查那些邻居  看有什么收获
Let's see what we can find out about those neighbors.
最好有人告诉我  是谁住在8楼B
And someone better tell me who the hell lives in 8-B.
我猜猜  是奶奶烧的吧
Let me guess. Gran cooked.
-印度香料鸡   -飓风玛莎在哪儿
- Chicken masala.  - And where is Hurricane Martha?
她的房间  享受着戏剧性的沉默
In her room taking a dramatic pause.
像往常一样  把外面这堆交给别人清理
Leaving the mess for everyone else to clean up, as usual.
我无所谓  晚餐很有趣
I don't mind. Dinner was fun.
这是我们的家  不是她的
Well, it's our room, not hers...
你得记住这点
Just remember.
就算她买了那些无比难看的床单
Even despite that hideous bedspread she bought.
你饿不饿  这还剩了好多饭菜
If you're hungry, there are lots of leftovers.
谢谢  我在回家路上吃了
Oh, thank you. I grabbed a slice on the way home.
你是真的当警察了
You really are turning into a cop.
真的  真这么觉得
Yeah?  Do you think?
那么今天谁遇害了
So who got killed today?
一位保姆
The nanny.
他们知道是谁干的吗
Do they know who did it?
显然  在真实的谋杀案中
Well, apparently in an actual homicide,
只有抓住凶手  警察知道是谁干的
They don't know who did it until after the guy gets caught.
为什么我们家从来没有保姆
How come we never had a nanny?
你妈妈和我觉得
Well, your mother and I decided
如果总会有人把你教坏
If someone was gonna screw you up,
那还是让我来做吧
We wanted it to be me.
不知道为什么  你现在却是如此优秀
Only you managed to turn out fine somehow anyway.
太出乎意料了
Surprisingly.
是不是我浪子回头的儿子
Is that the prodigal son I hear,
下了晚班回家了
Returned from working the night shift?
今天抓到嫌犯了吗  小子
You catch any perps today, kiddo?
我客串过一集纽约重案组  记得吗
I did an "NYPD Blue" once, remember?
你演的是无家可归的疯癫女人
You were the crazy homeless woman.
而且某些人觉得她现在还是
And some might say still are.
我刚才在问爸爸
I was just asking Dad
我小时候为什么没有保姆
How come we never had a nanny when I was little.
我给她分享了我的个人经验
I spared her any stories of my own personal experience.
当时我还是全天开工的女演员
I had a real job as a working actress.
不是每个人都可以坐在家里
You know, not everybody can sit at home
整天对着电脑  就能挣钱的
In front of a laptop and claim to be employed.
真的  你以前有保姆
Really? You had a nanny?
对  不过我们不叫她们保姆
Yeah, only we didn't call 'em nannies then.
那叫她们什么
What were they called?
我忘了
Oh, I don't know. Um...
酒鬼
Alcoholics?
暴躁的疯子  不  等等
Raving lunatics? No, no, no, wait.
是完全不负责任的中年女人
Uh, completely irresponsible middle-aged women who,
在她去拍戏的时候  本应负责照看我
Instead of looking after me while you were acting,
却完全不负责任
Like they were supposed to,
大白天  只看电视
Instead watched daytime television.
别抱怨了  可你一点也没变坏啊
Oh, stop your whining. You didn't turn out half bad.
别忘了  好的那一半都是我的基因
And don't forget, the good half are my genes.
关于这点
Well, that's just something we'll have to
也只能相信你了  不是吗
Take your word for, isn't it?
妈妈  我不是要你道歉
But I'm not asking for an apology, mother.
事实上  我第一本小说的情节
Actually, I got the plot of my first novel...
来自于观看肥皂剧  只此一生
By watching "One life to live."
又来了
There you go.
贝克特探长  这么快就想我了
Detective Beckett, did you miss me already?
也就是说你的成功里
Which means I am one- quarter responsible
也有我四分之一的功劳
For your success as well.
真的  他们晚上做这个
Really? Do they do those at night?
不  当然来
No, for sure.
你想到我  我真是太感动了
I'm just-- I'm just touched that you thought of me.
奉命给我打电话  明白了
Oh, ordered to call me? I see.
无论如何  我马上就过来
Well, either way. I, uh, can leave right away.
好的  我得走了
Okay. Gotta go.
别等我了  11点之前睡吧
I would say don't wait up, but you'll be asleep by 11:00.
十点半  明天要上学
10:30. It's a school night.
你确定她有我或你的基因吗
Are you sure she's got either one of our genes?
你会帮她洗盘子的吧
You will help her with the dishes?
好的  小心点  大警察
All right. Be careful... Flatfoot.
来  穿上这个
Here, put these on.
真的吗
Really?
我以为警察只是站在尸体旁
I thought cops just stood around the body
边吃火腿三明治  边开玩笑而已
Eating ham sandwiches and cracking jokes
就是那种不适当的黑色幽默
You know, hard-core gallows humor.
头部外伤无疑导致了死亡
The head trauma definitely contributed to the death.
猛烈的撞击
The force of the blows
造成严重的脑出血
Resulted in significant cerebral hemorrhaging.
卡塞尔先生  很高兴再次见到你
Mr. Castle, nice to see you again.
我也很想这么说
I wish I could say the same,
不过这眼镜都有划痕了
But my glasses are all scratchy.
他们多久换一次这个
How often do they let you replace these?
不是每个人都有你那么多预算的  卡塞尔
Not everybody has your budget, Castle.
她是怎么死的
So what killed her?
我认为  她是先被那瓶漂白液打中了头
I'd say she was struck in the head with the bleach bottle,
往前摔倒的时候  太阳穴撞到了桌角
Then fell forward, hit her temple on the edge of the table.
导致了颞部出血
That caused temporal bleeding.
因为没有急救  所以她失去了活下来的机会
Without medical attention, she didn't stand a chance.
不过我有你可能会感兴趣的发现
But what I thought you might find really interesting
她在死亡前几小时内  有过性行为
Is the fact that she had sex hours before her death.
-性行为  -我待会儿再给你解释
- Sex? - i'll explain how that works later.
甚至可能是在被杀前的几分钟内
Might have even been within a few minutes of the murder.
因为干衣机的高温  很难精确计算出时间点
The heat from the dryer makes it hard to pinpoint.
你是说她被强奸了
So you're saying she was raped?
很难说  并没有发现阴道撕裂
Hard to determine. There were no vaginal lacerations
也没有发现任何精液
Or presence of any semen.
那她有过性行为的证据是
So what's the evidence of sex?
微量杀精剂  那人用了避孕套
Traces of spermicide. The guy wore a condom.
天啊  你很久没试过了吧
Boy, it really has been a long time for you, hasn't it?
我想  可能是强奸
I mean, it could have been a rape,
-但我认为  -她认识那人
- but my best guess is... - She knew the guy.
没有外伤的迹象
Without evidence of trauma,
我可不相信凶手进行了性侵犯
I'm not ready to buy our attacker as a sexual predator,
特别是他还用了避孕套
Especially with him using a condom.
他可能是不想让人发现DNA
Could be he's trying to hide D.N.A.
伙计  如果有人聪明到不留下DNA
Dude, someone smart enough to hide D.N.A.
不对  你忽略了一点
No, you're missing the point.
洗衣房给了他作案的机会
The laundry room afforded opportunity.
她在那里被杀不是意外
It wasn't an accident she was killed there.
埃斯波西托  她的手机查得怎么样了
Esposito, where are we on her cell phone?
我查到了她的记录
I pulled her records,
让服务商确定了一下具体位置
Had her service provider pin it.
三角定位表明  手机就在大楼内或是附近
Triangulation puts it at or near the building.
可能他把手机抢走不让她呼救
Yeah, well, maybe he took it so she couldn't call for help,
再扔在附近的某处
Then dumped it somewhere close by.
前男友查得怎么样
What about her ex-boyfriend?
只知道他叫布兰特
We have a first name-- Brent.
如果找到手机
But if we had her cell phone,
电话本里应该有他
He might be in the address book.
这些电话怎么回事
What about these calls?
什么电话
What calls?
过去两个月内
Last two months,
有个号码打了几十通电话进来
There's dozens of incoming calls from the same number.
没错  我们还在查
Right. We're still running that down,
但那个号码是预付费的
But the number's a prepay.
还有  那个号码在她遇害前几周
Besides, those calls stopped coming
就没再打来了
A couple weeks before she was killed.
但是死者很早就
Yeah, but the outgoing calls to that number
不再打给那个号码
Stop even before that.
不管是谁  她不想理他们
Whoever it was, she didn't want to talk to them.
她把电话都转到了语音信箱
She was letting it go to voice mail.
去找这个布兰特  带来问问
Find this Brent. Bring him in for questioning.
你只是受邀到这里
You're here by invitation only.
明白吗
Got it?
-明白  -很好
- Got it. - Good.
布兰特 ·约翰逊
Brent Johnson?
我是凯特·贝克特探长  这位是卡塞尔先生
I'm detective Kate Beckett. This is... Mr. Castle.
我想你知道为什么请你过来
I suppose you know why you're here.
把我从公司带来的警官说
Um, the cops that picked me up at my job said
你们想问我关于莎拉的事
You had some questions about what happened to Sara.
据我了解  你们谈过恋爱
I understand that the two of you were dating?
对  直到一个月以前
Yeah, till about a month ago.
一个月前  后来发生了什么
A month ago? What happened then?
-没什么  我们分手了  -谁提出来的
- Nothing. We broke up. - Whose idea was that?
是双方都这么想的
It was a mutual thing, I guess.
双方
A mutual thing?
莎拉  是我  打给我好吗
Hey, Sara, it's me. Well, just call me back, okay?
你不能不回我电话  莎拉  别犯贱了
You can't just not call me  back, Sara. Don't be a bitch.
别这样  莎拉  我只想和你谈谈
Come on, Sara, I just want to talk to you.
听着  我不知道你为什么不肯告诉我
Look, I don't know why you can't just tell me
那家伙到底是谁
Who this other guy is.
你知道吗  你就是个荡妇
You know... You know what? You're just a little slut.
还有很多这样的留言
There's plenty more of those.
让亚历克·鲍德温的留言(影星怒骂女儿被曝)
Yep. They make Alec Baldwin's messages
听着像是美好的童话故事
Sound like rainbows and unicorns.
你们怎么弄到这些的
How did you get those?
-从你的服务商那里  -给个小建议
- From your service provider. - A little advice--
你买预付费手机的时候  别刷信用卡
When you buy a prepaid phone, don't use your credit card.
因为那是会被追查到的
Makes it totally traceable.
我没想隐瞒任何事
I wasn't trying to hide anything.
没有吗  那你为什么要撒谎
No? Then why did you just lie to me?
因为没有一个男人愿意被甩
'Cause no man likes getting dumped.
我说的对吗  我们的自尊心无法面对
Am I right? Our egos can't handle it.
有一次  我的前女友对我不忠
This one time I had an ex-girlfriend cheat on me,
我整整一星期都醉醺醺的
I drank every meal for a week.
我甚至都没喜欢过她
I didn't even like her.
要是我真的爱上她  天啊  我不知道
If I had loved her? Wow. I don't know...
会做出什么事来
What I would have done.
不  不是这样的
No, no. No way. It wasn't like that.
不是  如果你们在一个月之前就分手了
Oh, no. So then how did you find out about Sara
那你是怎么找到莎拉的
If you two broke up a month ago?
一个朋友帮忙的  克洛伊  克洛伊·理查森
From a friend. Chloe. Chloe Richardson.
我们是大学同学
All right? We all went to college together.
就是克洛伊帮莎拉找到工作的
Chloe's the one who got Sara her job.
这个朋友怎么找到她的
And how did this friend find out?
克洛伊在那栋楼的另一户人家做保姆
Chloe nannies for another family in the building.
她们俩关系很好
The two of 'em are pretty close.
莎拉被害那天  你在哪里
So then where were you the day that Sara got killed?
我就在警察找到我的地方  在上班
I was where those other cops found me, at my job.
那里有监视器
Look, we have video cameras there
还有签到表
And a sign-in sheet.
我和这事毫无关系
Look, I didn't have anything to do with this.
我被捕了吗
Am I under arrest or something?
没有  你可以走了
No. You can go.
不过  在我们下次见面之前别出城
But... Just don't leave town until we speak again.
明白吗
Do you understand?
是的  警官
Yeah. Yes, Ma'am.
别出城
"Don't leave town"?
不是需要正当理由才能那样说吗
Don't you need probable cause for something like that?
但他不知道  不是吗
Only he doesn't know that, does he?
你可以那样撒谎  太酷了
You can lie like that? That is so cool.
卡塞尔
Castle.
门卫告诉埃斯波西托这是个儿童游乐场
Doorman told Esposito that this is the playground
这栋楼的所有保姆都会来这儿
That all the nannies of the building go to.
我们应该能在这儿找到克洛伊
So hopefully we find Chloe here.
这让我想起不久的过去
This brings me back a bit.
不久  应该是很久吧  卡塞尔
A bit? I'm thinking it's a little more than that, Castle.
我不是说我小的时候
I wasn't talking about when I was a kid.
我是说
I'm talking about
以前常带我女儿去公园
When I used to take my daughter to the park.
你经常带女儿去公园
You used to take your daughter to the park?
春天夏天秋天  我们每天都去
Spring, summer, fall. We were here every day.
阿丽克西斯的妈妈在社区剧院工作
Alexis' mom was doing community theater.
她经常出差  所以我照顾孩子  怎么了
She was on the road a lot, so I had custody. What?
没什么  只是没想到你还是奶爸一族
Nothing. I just never figured you for Mr. Mom.
那是我人生中最快乐的日子
Some of the best days of my life.
-好像还真不错  -跟我说说
- That's actually kind of nice. - Yeah, tell me about it.
你知道在曼哈顿的儿童游乐场里
Do you know how many lonely single mothers there are
有多少孤独的单身母亲吗
On a Manhattan playground?
没有婚姻的日子里  我也在那里
And there I was, between marriages.
卡塞尔  你到底结过几次婚
Exactly how many times have you been married, Castle?
-两次  -没了
- Twice. - That's it?
不够吗  你呢
Isn't that enough? How about you?
我  从来没有
Me? No, never been.
-真的  -对
- Really?  - Yeah.
你应该很在行才对
You'd be good at it.
你有控制欲  还满腹不满
You're both controlling and disapproving.
你真该试试
You should really try it.
卡塞尔  我不认为第一次的失败
I'm not an "if defeated at first,
等于永远失败
You don't succeed" kind of a girl, Castle.
但在婚姻上
When it comes to marriage,
我更相信打一场赢一场
I'm more of a "one and done" type.
有中意的候选人了吗
Any serious candidates?
贝佳
Becca!
门卫说她穿了件红色马甲
The doorman said she'd have a red vest on.
应该就是她了
That might be our girl.
去吧  去吧
Go, go, go!
是克洛伊吗
Chloe?
贝克特探长  有几个关于莎拉·曼宁的问题
I'm Detective Beckett. I was wondering if I could ask you
可以问你一下吗
Some questions about Sara Manning.
现在吗
Um, right... Right now?
对  不会耽误你很久的
Yeah, it won't take long.
好的  玛吉  能帮我看一下贝佳吗
Yeah, uh, Maggie? Can you watch Becca for a sec?
莎拉男朋友告诉我们  你帮她找的工作
Sara's boyfriend told us that you helped her get her job.
你们见过布兰特了
Uh, you talked to Brent?
没错  我们毕业的时候
Yeah, when... When we got out of school,
莎拉找不到工作
Sara couldn't find work.
她到处打临时工
She was temping all over town.
我在那栋楼做保姆
I nanny for a family in the same building
听说彼得森一家想找保姆
And heard that the Petersons were looking for someone.
你最后一次见莎拉是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Sara?
克洛伊  我明白失去朋友的感觉
I know what it feels like to lose somebody, Chloe,
但我们必须问你这些问题
But we need to ask you these questions.
有时候我们在上班前先碰头
Um, sometimes we'd meet up before work,
一起去哥伦布咖啡店买咖啡
Get a coffee on Columbus
然后一起走去上班
And then walk over to work together.
-那天你们去买咖啡了吗  -是的
- Did you get coffee that day?  - Yeah.
她对你说过什么吗
Did she say anything to you?
她有没看起来心烦  或者
Did she seem upset? Or...
心烦  烦什么
Upset? Upset about what?
布兰特告诉我们
Brent gave us the impression
说莎拉正在和别人约会
That Sara was seeing someone else.
你肯定知道是谁  对吗
You know who it was, don't you?
有时候莎拉会待到很晚
Sometimes Sara would stay late.
在哪儿待到很晚  彼得森家吗
Stay late where, at the Petersons'?
对  我们差不多同时下班
Yeah, we got off work around the same time,
所以我们一起坐地铁回家
So we'd take the train home together.
我和别人合租  离莎拉的住处只有几个街区
I live with a roommate a couple blocks from Sara.
只是最近几个月  她总是很晚才走
Only the last few months, she'd been staying late.
彼得森太太和她丈夫轮流
Mr. And Mrs. Peterson kind of take turns
回家吃饭
Coming home for dinner, you know?
是的  彼得森太太告诉我们了
Yeah, Mrs. Peterson told us.
天啊  我真的不想说这些
God. I- I don't want to say something, and then...
我是说  他已经结婚了
I mean-- I mean, he's married.
等一下  莎拉告诉过你他的事
Wait a minute. Sara told you about him?
没有  没有明说  只是
No. No, not exactly. It's just...
彼得森太太不回家吃饭的那些晚上
The nights Mrs. Peterson didn't come home for dinner...
就是莎拉晚下班的时候
Those were the only nights Sara stayed late.
我也说过
And I told you
我喜欢先了解情况
That I like to question my most likely suspects
再盘问我觉得最有嫌疑的人
After I know more about them.
那样就会得到更加具体的答案
That way they're tied to more specific answers.
你也怀疑是他
You suspected him, too?
丈夫吗  当然
The husband? Duh.
你真应该参加我的扑克游戏
You would really clean up at my poker game.
是啊  你  詹姆斯·帕特森(犯罪小说作家)
Right. You, James Patterson
还有纽约时报评出的其他畅销作家
And the rest of the "Times" best seller list?
多谢了  卡塞尔  对我来说太高攀了
Thank you, Castle. Little too rich for my blood.
我们也可以玩脱衣扑克
We could always make it strip poker.
不好意思  比起神秘我更喜欢恐怖
Sorry, but I prefer mystery to horror.
不  是的  我现在就在这里
No, yeah, I’m-- I'm in the space right now,
我告诉过你们
But like I told you guys,
我至少需要20000平方英尺的地方
I'm gonna need at least 20,000 square feet.
我  听着  我等一下再打给你们
I... Listen, I'm gonna give you guys a call back.
我会告诉你顾客是否满意  好吗
I'll let you know if the client is interested, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
你好  记得我们吗
Hi. Remember us?
彼得森先生  最后一次见到莎拉是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Sara, Mr. Peterson?
她被害的前一天晚上  我告诉过你们了
The night before she was killed. I told you that.
那天是你回家吃饭  对吗
Which was your night to be home for dinner, right?
对  为什么问这个
Right. W- Why are you asking?
彼得森先生
Well, Mr. Peterson...
从我们掌握的情况看
We have information that suggests
莎拉·曼宁正在和人交往
That Sara Manning was having a relationship.
没错  她有个男朋友
Right. She had a boyfriend.
另有其人
Someone else.
另有其人  谁
Someone else? Who?
我  你是说我和莎拉有染
Me? You think I was having an affair with Sara?
-说对了  -简直是胡扯
- Bingo. - That is-- that's crazy.
是吗  我们得知她有时候会晚下班
Is it? We know that she stayed late some nights.
对  她给我们做晚餐
Right. She helped us make dinner.
我们  我们听到的是
"Us"? Well, what we heard was that she helped
只有你妻子不在家的时候  她会晚下班
On the nights that your wife wasn't home.
首先  不是你们想的那样
First of all, it's not what you think.
什么时候是过呢
When is it ever?
没错  我有外遇
Yes, I was having an affair.
发生了什么
So what happened?
什么意思  我对妻子不忠  我出轨了
What do you mean, what happened? I cheated. I strayed.
随便你怎么说
Whatever you want to call it.
我是说在洗衣房发生了什么
I mean in the laundry room.
什么
What?
-你刚才说  -对  我是有外遇
- You just said that you  - Yes, I was having an affair,
但不是和莎拉  天哪
But it wasn't with Sara, for god sakes.
是和我办公室里的另一个女同事
It was with another woman in my office.
每次轮到我应该
Look, every night that I was
回家吃饭的时候  我都没有回去
Supposed to be home having dinner, I wasn't.
你们可以去查我家的电话记录
You can check the landlines from the apartment.
每次我都会打电话  确认莎拉的情况
I called to make sure that Sara was okay every night.
你们可以  查手机通话记录  对吗
You can...you can check cell phone records, right?
别出城
Don't leave town.
丈夫查得怎么样
Hey, what happened with the husband?
有外遇  但不是和被害人
Oh, he was cheating, just not with our victim.
你查查这个  这是那女人的名字
Here, I need you to run it down. This is her name.
所以我说  承诺这回事早就不复存在了
I'm telling you, true commitment's a thing of the past.
你说说有哪对夫妇是开心的
I mean, name one happily married couple.
蒂珍妮丝和德罗西(著名主持人和同性女友)
Degeneres and De Rossi.
他比你厉害  伙计
Ooh, I think he's got you there, bro.
这是什么  观点(著名谈话节目)
What is this,"The View"?
男朋友查得怎么样
Where are we on the boyfriend?
不在场证明证实了  有录像和签到表
His story checks out. Video and a sign-In sheet.
好吧  现在就只剩出轨的丈夫可查
Great. So now all we have is a cheating husband
他可能也有不在场证明
With a possible alibi
没有手机能追查嫌犯的指纹
And no cell phone to run the perp's fingerprints.
我有个好点儿消息
I got something better.
拜托告诉我  市长想把他从这儿弄走
Please tell me it's that the mayor wants him outta here.
发现没  一旦在没有嫌犯可查
Have you ever noticed how she gets a little grumpy
她就有点暴躁
When she doesn't have a suspect?
现在有了
Well, we got one now.
猜猜谁对莎拉遇害那天的行踪
Guess who wasn't where they say they were
没有说实话
The day Sara Manning was killed?
谁
Who?
拜托  你得先猜
Come on, you gotta guess.
瑞恩  瑞恩  我不猜
Ryan. Ryan. I'm not guessing.
知道吗  你可真扫兴
You're a killjoy, you know that?
我一直都这么说她
Exactly what I’ve been telling her.
不可能吧
No way.
挺不错的吧  告诉过你要先猜的
Pretty good, huh? Told you you should've guessed.
莎拉·曼宁遇害那天
You weren't at the office
你不在你的办公室  是吗
The day Sara Manning was killed, were you?
你对我们说了谎  彼得森太太
You lied to me, Mrs. Peterson.
瑞恩警官跟你儿子的学校核实过
Detective Ryan checked with your son's school.
那天他们打电话通知你莎拉没去学校
The day they called about Sara not showing up,
你的助手说和你联系不上
Your assistant said that you were unreachable.
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说莎拉·曼宁的事  彼得森太太
I'm talking about Sara Manning, Mrs. Peterson.
在说你为什么要说谎
We're talking about why you lied
以及那天你究竟身处何地
About where you were the day she was killed.
我们已经知道你不在办公室
And we know you weren't in your office.
你可以很容易偷偷溜进大楼
It would have been easy to sneak into the building.
可能趁门卫出去
Doorman could have been outside
叫出租车或是收包裹
Hailing a cab, taking a delivery
等等
Wait...
我丈夫有外遇
My husband is having an affair.
你们知道吗
Did you know that?
事实上  我们已经知道了
Actually, we did.
好几个月了  我居然都不知道
All these months, I had no idea.
但是后来你发现了
But then you found out.
对  莎拉几星期前告诉我的
Yeah, Sara told me a few weeks ago.
莎拉告诉你这件事的
Sara told you about the affair?
对  她为了瞒着我
Yes, and she'd been an absolute wreck
搞得神经紧张
About keeping it from me.
是啊  肯定是这样
Yeah, I bet she was.
你们知道他额外付给她钱吗
Did you know he was paying her extra?
不  他没提到
No, he didn't mention that.
真无法想象居然让莎拉做这种事
Imagine putting Sara in the middle of something like that.
什么事
Something like what?
让莎拉帮他打掩护
Well, using Sara to cover for himself.
太恶心了
I mean, it's disgusting.
我不明白  彼得森太太
I don't understand, Mrs. Peterson.
如果你和莎拉的死毫无关系
If you had nothing to do with Sara's death,
那为什么撒谎
Then why would you lie?
因为我那出轨的丈夫
Because my cheating husband has no idea
完全不知道我准备跟他离婚
I'm about to serve him with divorce papers.
我说谎  是因为当时我在律师那里
I lied because I was at my lawyer's that afternoon.
不是只有霍华德才有秘密
Howard's not the only one who can keep a secret.
你好
Hello there!
在忙什么呢
What are you up to?
没什么
Nothing.
我希望不是又在视频聊天啊
You're not webcamming again, I hope.
我把监控录像刻成了DVD
I burned a DVD from security cameras...
是警方在调查的证物
That the police are looking at.
而且我从来没视频聊天
And I’ve never webcammed.
那是你的说法  你还要坚持是吧
That's your story, and you're sticking to it, huh?
警察会让你把证物刻成DVD
The police just let you burn a DVD?
你该意识到
You do realize you're gonna
不能再偷警方的证据了吧
Have to stop stealing evidence, right?
我以为  你之所以跟着
I thought the whole purpose of following
这个女警探
This detective around
只是为了帮助你写作
Was to help you to write.
这叫研究  妈妈
It's called research, mother.
好吧  你最好希望
Well, you'd better hope
德里克·斯道姆系列最后一本能大卖  亲爱的
This last Derrick Storm book sells, lover boy,
因为研究可不能用来付  账单
Because research don't pay the... Bills.
这是那个保姆吗
Is that the nanny?
有哪个正常的已婚女人
What married woman in her right mind
会把这样漂亮的女孩带回家
Invites a girl that pretty into her own home?
你们在看什么
What are you guys watching?
我在看  她在搅和
I'm watching. She's butting in.
警方找不到保姆的手机
The police can't find the nanny's cell phone.
他们觉得上面可能会有罪犯的指纹
They were hoping to lift some fingerprints from it.
看得到她下楼去洗衣房时
I just thought I could see it she had it with her
是拿着手机的
When she went down to the laundry room.
然后呢
And?
拿衣服送洗时
It's in her hand
手机就在手里
The first time she brings the clothes down to the wash,
要去烘干衣服的时候
But then she doesn't have it
手机却不在了
When she goes down to use the dryer.
所以  她可能把手机
So... She probably left it
丢在楼上她工作的那家了
Upstairs in the apartment where she worked.
他们说找不到  等等
They say they can't fi... Find it. Wait a sec.
什么
What?
这当中有5秒钟的差别
There's a 5- second time difference.
什么5秒钟的差别
A 5-Second time difference in what?
她两次乘电梯去地下室
She rides the elevator twice to the basement.
第一次是去洗衣服
The first time to put the clothes in the washer,
第二次是去烘干衣服
The second time to put them in the dryer.
但是第二次下楼
Only the second time,
她多花了5秒
The trip takes her five seconds longer.
为什么一样的路程要多花时间
Why would it take her longer to travel the same distance?
不会的
It wouldn't.
我不明白你要干什么  卡塞尔
I'm not quite sure where you're going with this, Castle.
好的  32秒
All right, 32 seconds.
花了32秒钟
It takes 32 seconds
从地下室到12楼
To get from the basement to the 12th floor.
太好了  我会布告天下
Great. I'll alert the media.
但是第二次  她花了37秒
Only the second time, it took her 37 seconds.
为什么会多出5秒
Why would it take her five extra seconds?
因为第二次
Because the second time,
她不是从12楼下去的
She wasn't coming from the 12th floor.
她应该是从
She was coming from the...
15楼
15th floor?
这说不通啊  彼得森一家住在12楼
This doesn't make any sense. The Petersons live on 12.
不过我敢肯定  用避孕套的人就住在15楼
Yeah, but I bet the guy who wears that condom lives on 15.
顺便说一句  乘电梯的事
By the way, that whole elevator thing?
我这么做  是因为你身上的清香
I just did that 'cause you smell nice.
卡塞尔  你不能就这样敲别人的门
Castle, you can't just knock on people's doors.
为什么不行
Why not?
谁啊
Who is it?
因为你会吓着他们的
Because you're gonna freak them out.
警察
Police!
你们是警察吗
You're the police?
她是
Uh, she is.
抱歉  您是一个人住吗
I'm sorry. Do you live here alone?
对  你为什么问这个
Yeah. Why you wanna know?
别担心  你不够年轻
Uh, don't worry about it. You're not young enough.
什么不够年轻
Young enough for what?
做爱
To have sex.
你们到底算什么警察
Uh, what kind of cops did you say you were?
他不是  我是警察
He's not a cop. I'm a cop.
你们想找人上床吗
And you're looking for someone to have sex with?
卡塞尔  快看
Castle, look.
真抱歉打搅您
So sorry to bother you.
77岁也不是没可能啊  知道吗
77 ain't beyond the realm of possibility, ya know?
请问  这小女孩是贝佳吗
Pardon me, is this little girl Becca?
对不起  我不太明白
I'm sorry. I'm not sure I'm following.
我们认为在莎拉·曼宁遇害前
Prior to her murder,
她是从这层楼下楼的
We believe that Sara Manning was coming from this floor.
我不清楚  我那天上班
Well, I don't know anything about that. I was at work.
可能她上来看克洛伊
Maybe she came up to see Chloe?
克洛伊·理查森
Chloe Richardson?
她和莎拉是好朋友
She and Sara were friends,
有时两家的孩子一起过玩伴日
And our kids get together sometimes for playdates.
亲爱的  怎么了  我以为你出去了
Hey, babe. What's going on? I thought you were going out.
-这是警察  -警察
- It's the police. - Police?
他们认为克洛伊的朋友莎拉  在被害那天
They think Chloe's friend Sara might've been up here
可能上来过
The day she was killed.
等等  你那天在家  对吧
Wait, you were home that day, right? .
是哪天啊
Um... What day was that?
星期二
Tuesday.
没错  我是在家
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I was... I was... I was here.
那你看见莎拉了吗
So did you see Sara?
我想没有  没有
I don't think so. No.
你想没有
You don't think so?
是的
No.
介意我用下洗手间吗
Mind if I use your bathroom?
人们从来没想过警察也是人
People never think about that.
警察什么时候上厕所
When do cops use the bathroom?
-就在那里  -谢谢
- It's right there. - Thank you.
那么  星期二
So... Tuesday.
对  让我想想
Oh, yeah, yeah. Let me think a minute. Um...
这么说你不能确定是有还是没有
So you're saying that you can't say one way or the other?
克洛伊来照顾贝佳以后
After Chloe got here to take care of Becca,
我就进房小睡了一会儿
I went inside to take a nap.
我都是晚上工作
I work most nights.
避孕套
Condoms.
哈里斯先生  您是做什么的
And what is it that you do, Mr. Harris?
我是个音乐家
Oh, I'm a musician.
洗手间里有避孕套
Condoms in the bathroom.
所以  有可能莎拉上来过
So anyway, it's possible that Sara was up here.
我只是  不太肯定
I just... Couldn't really say for sure.
或许你们应该问问克洛伊
You know, maybe you should  talk to Chloe about this.
我问过了
I already have.
她怎么说
And what did she tell you?
她说那天早些时候见过莎拉
She said that she saw Sara earlier in the day,
但她没提到
But she didn't say anything about
莎拉来过你们家
Sara being in your apartment.
那她还能上来干嘛
What else would she be doing up here?
什么声音
What is that?
像是谁的手机响了
That sounds like somebody's cell phone.
伊恩  这是谁的电话
Ian... Who the hell's phone is this?
为什么她的电话在你们的卧室
Why was her phone in your bedroom?
可能她落在那了  我真的不知道
Maybe she dropped it. I don't-- I don't-- I don't know.
你说过  你回房间睡觉
You told me you went into the bedroom to take a nap.
她怎么可能进到房间里  落下电话
How could she go into the room, drop the phone,
而你却没看见她
And you not see her?
她说得没错  你想想就知道这解释不通
She's right. It doesn't make sense when you think about it.
我们正在对你家药柜里的
We're running a test on the condoms
避孕套做测试
We found in your medicine cabinet.
现在有些你不想听的
Now there's something you never wanna hear.
如果杀精子剂匹配的话  你将被控谋杀
If the spermicide's a match, you're facing a murder charge.
我没杀莎拉
Well, I- I didn't kill Sara.
但是你跟她发生关系了
But you were sleeping with her.
我们是上床了
Look, we had sex, okay?
但莎拉离开我家的时候  她还好好的
But when Sara left my place, she was fine.
你跟踪她到地下室了  对不对
You followed her down to the basement, didn't you?
你跟踪她到了地下室
You followed her in the basement,
然后杀了她
And then you killed her.
不  我不会伤害莎拉
No! I wouldn't hurt Sara.
你不会伤害她
You wouldn't hurt her?
你这个已婚男人  在家跟她搞婚外情
You're a married man sleeping with her in your own bed.
她什么时候离开你家的
What time did she leave your apartment?
快到1点的时候
A little before 1:00.
你凭什么这么肯定
How can you be sure?
因为克洛伊每天一点左右
Because Chloe gets back from the park with Becca
带贝佳从公园回来吃午饭
Every day around 1:00 to give her her lunch.
莎拉大概在克洛伊回来的十分钟前离开
And Sara left maybe ten minutes before Chloe got back.
你们去问克洛伊  她能证明我当时在家
Look, you ask Chloe, she will tell you I was there.
我不可能杀莎拉的
There's no way that I could've killed Sara.
贝克特探长  我是弗兰克·加里森
Detective Beckett? Frank Garrison.
我是哈里斯先生的代表律师
I've been retained to represent Mr. Harris,
我的当事人
And I'm directing him
现在不回答你们的任何问题
Not to answer any more of your questions.
你的当事人要么在这里回答我的问题
Your client can answer my questions here
要么当着大陪审团的面回答
Or he can answer them  in front of a grand jury.
如果你们有足够证据控告他  就去告吧
If you've got enough to charge him, do it.
否则  他现在就要跟我走了
Otherwise, he's coming with me.
我们走吧  哈里斯先生
Let's go,Mr. Harris.
他们了解规则的时候
Guess it's a lot tougher
就难办多了吧
When they actually know the rules, huh?
谢谢
Thank you.
化验结果显示  避孕套是一样的
Lab says condoms are a match.
那能证明他们发生了关系
So we can prove they had sex?
但是  如果克洛伊一点钟到家
Look, if Chloe got home at 1:00,
他根本来不及
Then there's no way he had time
到地下室去
To get down to the basement,
杀掉莎拉再上楼
Kill Sara and make it back upstairs.
也许我们该请克洛伊过来
Maybe we ought to pick Chloe up
看看她怎么说
See if she backs his story.
这也不一定
We don't have to.
为什么
Why not?
因为电梯的摄像头有时间记录
Because the elevator cam had a time stamp.
疑犯说
Our suspect says that
莎拉12点45离开他家
Sara left his apartment about 12:45,
电梯里的录像显示
And the camera in the elevator
她12点48分进电梯去地下室
Puts her on it headed towards the basement at 12:48.
我们假设她于十分钟之后被杀
We think she was murdered maybe ten minutes later.
我们现在要找什么
So what are we looking for?
疑犯的保姆
The nanny who worked for the guy.
看看他说的是不是真的
We're just trying to check out his story.
他说保姆1点钟到家
He claims she got home at 1:00,
之后他再也没有出去过
And that he never left the apartment again.
找到了  12点54分
Ah, there she is. 12:54.
那是在莎拉·曼宁
Okay, that's six minutes after Sara Manning
进电梯六分钟之后
Got on the elevator.
这么说来  哈里斯说的是真话
Well, I guess Harris was telling the truth.
等等
Wait.
-怎么了  -等等 那个孩子在哪儿?
- What?  - Wait, where's the kid?
-哪个孩子  -贝佳
- Where's what kid? - Becca.
克洛伊照顾的那个小女孩
The little girl that Chloe takes care of.
也许她把她留在外面
Maybe she left the kid in playground
给另一个保姆照顾了
With one of the other nannies.
哈里斯说她每天
Harris said that she came back
按时把他女儿带回家
With his daughter at the same time every day.
那又有什么关系
What difference does it make?
世上没有巧合
The diffence is that there are no coincidences,
至少命案发生的时候没有
Not when murder's involved.
克洛伊知道莎拉的时间安排
Chloe would've known Sara's schedule
而且她知道
And Chloe would've known that
莎拉当时在地下室里
That Sara was in the basement at that time.
带她回来
Pick her up
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
克洛伊·理查森是不是住在这里
Does Chloe Richardson live here?
是的  但她现在不在
Yes, but she's not here right now.
她去哪儿了
Where did she go?
去城里了
Into the city.
你介意我四处看看吗
Do you mind if I take a look around?
不介意  但是她不在这里
No. But...  I'm telling you, she's not here.
她一小时之前就走了
She left about an hour ago.
探长
Detective.
这是克洛伊的雇主一家人
That's the family that Chloe works for.
并不是完整的一家人
Not exactly  the whole family.
没有包括孩子的妈妈
She cut the mom out of the picture.
克洛伊进城去哪儿了
Where in the city did Chloe go?
去他们家了
To their apartment.
她说他们今晚要她照顾小孩
She said that they needed her to babysit tonight.
她一定发现了  我把哈里斯带回去问话
She must've found out that I took Harris in for questioning.
如果她问过他老婆  就知道我们放了他
If she talked to his wife, she'd know he'd been released.
我们都知道
And we both know
她怎么对待她不喜欢的人
What she does to people she doesn't like.
她去找伊恩·哈里斯了
She's going after Ian Harris.
我们最好在她动手前找到她
We better find her before she finds him.
门卫给楼上打电话
No answer in the apartment
但是没人接
When the doorman called upstairs.
不过他确定克洛伊在里面
But he's sure Chloe's there.
他说伊恩·哈里斯也在上面
He says Ian Harris is up there, too.
他1小时前回来的
Came home about an hour ago.
也就是说克洛伊一直在等他
Which means Chloe would've been there waiting for him.
行了  没时间
All right, we don't have time
等紧急救援了
To wait for emergency services.
我们自己进去
We're gonna have to go in on our own.
他怎么办
Whoa. What about him?
他留在这儿
He stays here.
不行  拜托  拜托
Whoa! No! Come on! Come on!
我都签过弃权书了
I already signed my life away.
还要怎么样
What more do you want?
那行  卡塞尔  但只是陪同和观察
Okay, Castle, but it's accompany and observe,
不能参与和干扰  明白吗
Not participate and annoy. Got it?
虽然没那么好玩了  不过也可以
Participate and annoy's a lot more fun, but all right.
你跟在后面  待在走廊
And stay behind us in the hallway,
我不发话  别乱动
And don't move unless I tell you.
视死如归  你知道我是说
Hope to die. You know what I mean. It's...
门开着
Open door.
伙计们  有人受伤  准备好
I got a victim down, guys. Stack 'em up.
警察  纽约警察
Police! New York city police!
我们在这里
We're here! We're here!
哈里斯太太
Mrs. Harris?
在里面  我把我们锁在浴室里了
In here! I- I locked us in the bathroom.
房间里没人
Room all clear!
看看他怎么样
Check him!
哈里斯太太  你没事吧  你女儿跟你在一起吗
Mrs. Harris, are you okay? Is your daughter with you?
是的  我们没事
Yes. Yes, we're okay.
他还活着
He's still alive.
哈里斯太太  克洛伊在里面吗
Mrs. Harris, is Chloe there?
不在  只有我和贝佳
No, no, it's just me and Becca.
整间房子都没人  克洛伊不在这里
Apartment's all clear. Chloe's not here.
你现在可以出来了  哈里斯太太
You can come out now, Mrs. Harris.
克洛伊在哪里  哈里斯太太
Where's Chloe, Mrs. Harris?
我不知道
I don't know.
她肯定用了她的钥匙  我刚准备给贝佳洗澡
She must've used her key. I- I was just giving Becca a bath.
我都不知道她在这儿
I didn't even know she was here.
楼下的门卫打来的
That's the doorman from downstairs.
快接
Answer it.
你好
Hello.
谢谢  我会告诉她的
Thank you. I'll tell her.
门卫说有个租客打电话
Doorman says a tenant called.
说看见个女孩拿着把刀在洗衣房
There's a girl in the laundry  room, and she's got a knife.
那女孩儿在哪儿
Where's the girl?
坐在里面
She's inside, just sitting there.
埃斯波西托  让这些人离开
Esposito, get these people out of here.
走吧  大家都上楼吧
Let's go. Everybody up the stairs.
走吧  走吧
Come on, let's go.
准备怎么办
So what's the plan?
让所有人活着出去
To get everyone out this alive.
听起来不错
Good plan.
你不能进去  明白吗
You don't go in. Do you understand?
明白
Yes.
好
Okay.
克洛伊
Chloe?
克洛伊  我是贝克特探长  还记得我吗
Chloe, it's detective Beckett. Do you remember me?
你走开
Please just go away.
抱歉  克洛伊  我不会走的
I'm sorry, Chloe, but I can't do that.
克洛伊
Look, Chloe,
你受伤了
You're hurt.
把刀放下  让我来帮你好吗
Why don't you put the knife away, and let me help you?
你为什么不一枪打死我
Oh, why don't you just shoot me?
看着我  看着我
Hey, look at me. Look.
没人要开枪
No one's gonna shoot anyone.
知道吗
Okay?
卡塞尔  除非是你再走近一步
Unless it's you if you take another step inside, Castle.
他跟莎拉上床了
He was sleeping with Sara.
我知道
I know.
他一直  都只跟我在一起
Only the-- the whole time, He was sleeping with me.
他还一直告诉我  他爱的是我
And he was telling me that he loved me,
他要为了我离开她老婆
That he was gonna leave his wife for me.
男人有时候就是这样的  克洛伊
Guys can be like that sometimes, Chloe.
他们会说谎  我知道当你发现真相的时候
They can lie, and I know when you find out
会有多么伤心
How much it could break your heart.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
这样我就更要帮你了
Well,that's even more reason for us to get you some help.
对吗
Right?
我只不过想跟她谈谈
I just wanted to talk to her.
没有别的
That's all.
我只不过想告诉她  我和伊恩很相爱
I just wanted to-- to tell her that Ian and I were in love.
我知道莎拉的事不过是个意外  克洛伊
I know what happened to Sara was an accident, Chloe.
我明白
I know that.
我把贝佳留在公园里  一个人上楼
I left Becca in the park, and I went up to the apartment
我想知道这是不是真的  因为
To see if it was true,'cause, uh...
我记得他看着她的样子
I'd seen the way he was looking at her.
一看到伊恩的床  我就知道了
As soon as I saw Ian's bed, I knew.
他去洗澡了  所以我...
He went to take a shower, so I--
我就下来
I came down here,
只想跟莎拉谈谈
Just to talk to Sara.
我知道你不是有意要杀她的  克洛伊
I know you didn't mean to kill her, Chloe.
莎拉是我的朋友  你知道吗
Sara was my friend, you know?
但是她  她没有
But she just-- she didn't...
她不懂
She didn't get it.
她不懂我们之间的感情
She didn't get how we felt about each other.
所以当她  转身的时候
So when-- when she turned around,
我抓起那瓶漂白液  砸向她
I just... Grabbed the bleach, and I hit her with it.
她倒下了
And she fell.
我太害怕了  我不
And I was so scared. I didn't...
不知道应该怎么办  所以我就
I didn't know what to do, so I just...
把她放进干衣机
I put her in the dryer.
我太生气了
I was so angry...
很生气
You know, just so mad.
克洛伊  把刀放下  我会帮你的
Chloe, put the knife down, okay, and let me help you.
把刀放下就好了
Just put the knife down.
来吧
Come on.
我太愚蠢了
God, I'm so stupid.
没事了
It's okay.
现在貌似我熬过来了
So... Looks like I managed to make it through the case
没受伤也没中枪  活得好好的
Without getting injured, shot or killed.
大概明天吧
Yeah, well, maybe tomorrow.
顺便说一下  我很喜欢你回忆的
By the way, I really liked that whole,
姐妹情深的那些
Uh, sisterhood thing you ran back there.
我没有回忆什么  卡塞尔
I wasn't running anything, Castle.
是那个男人造成这一切
What that guy did had consequences,
但他却可以转身离开
Only he'll get just walk away.
也不是没受到惩罚
Well, not scot-Free.
我感觉得到
I mean, I- I sense
未来他老婆会跟他要一大笔赡养费
A pretty big divorce settlement in his future.
无论怎样  都不能弥补他的错
Whatever it is, it won't be enough.
一旦  她的心碎了
Moment was... Her heart had once been broken.
你们抓到他了吗
So... Did you guys get him?
说话这会儿  他们正在去监狱的路上
On their way up the river as we speak.
真酷  是你之前以为的那个人吗
Cool. Was it who you thought?
事实上  不是
Actually, it wasn't.
不错的故事  出乎你的意料
It must've been a pretty good story to surprise you.
你知道的  你最好小心一点
You know, you better be careful
否则  你会变得和你的读者一样
Or you'll turn into one of your readers.
行啦行啦  现在不会了
Oh. Oh, okay, you just ruined it.
有时候  意外也是很棒的
You know, it's okay to be surprised sometimes.
那才有乐趣
That's the fun.
你就是我的惊喜
You surprise me,
一直都是
All the time.
明早见  爸爸
I'll see you in the morning, dad.
晚安  南瓜
Good night, pumpkin.
爸
Dad?
谢谢你当我的奶爸
Thanks for being my nanny.
不客气  孩子
No sweat, kiddo.